Guide to the Robin Morgan Papers, 1940s-2019 and undated, bulk 1970-2019 RL.00913
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1940s-2002 and undated
  - Sisterhood is Global Subseries, 1978-1997 and undated
    - Contributors (Box W12)
      - Giri, Manjula (Nepal), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W12)
      - Goonatilake, Hema (Sri Lanka), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W12)
      - La Gonave, Cacos (Haiti), 1983 and undated (Box W12)
      - Green, Rayne (USA), 1980-1983 and undated (Box W12)
    - Contributors (Box W13)
      - Griffin Vanessa (Pacific Islands), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W13)
      - de Hedervary, Claire (UN), 1979-1982 (Box W13)
      - Habib, Miriam (Pakistan), 1981-1997 (Box W13)
      - Hassouna, Fawzia Y. (Palestinian Women), 1982-1984 and undated, 2 folders (Box W13)
      - Higuchi, Keiko (Japan), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W13)
      - Hirata, Lucy Cheng (China), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W13)
      - Ivekovic, Rada (Yugoslavia), 1982-1984 and undated (Box W13)
      - Jain, Devaki (India), 1981-1986 and undated (Box W13)
    - Contributors (Box W14)
      - Kantai, Terry (Kenya), 1982 and undated (Box W14)
      - Kolb, Ingrid and Marie Louise Janssen-Jurriet (West Germany), 1981-1984 and undated (Box W14)
      - Konie, Gwen (Zambia), 1980-1984 and undated (Box W14)
      - Korosi, Suzanne (Hungary), 1978-1984 and undated (Box W14)
      - LaFontant, Marie-Carmel (Haiti), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W14)
      - Liljestrom, Rita (Sweden), 1978-1983 and undated (Box W14)
      - Lugo, Carmen and M.A. Rascon (Mexico), 1982-1985 and undated, 2 folders (Box W14)
      - Mamonova, Tatyana (USSR), 1981-1987 and undated, 2 folders (Box W14)
      - McCafferty, Nell (Ireland), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W14)
    - Contributors (Box W15)
      - Mernissi, Fatima (Morocco), 1979-1994 and undated (Box W15)
      - Merola R., Giovanna (Venezuela), 1982-1986 (Box W15)
      - Morgner, Irmtraud (E. Germany), 1982-1983 and undated (Box W15)
      - Minai, Naila and Dr. Gulcin Kandemir (Turkey), 1982-1984 and undated (Box W15)
      - Muchena, Olivia (Zimbabwe), 1980-1984 and undated (Box W15)
      - Nemiroff, Greta (Canada), 1978-1989 and undated (Box W15)
      - Ogundipe, Molara (Nigeria), 1982-1984 and undated (Box W15)
      - Oudijk, Corrine (the Netherlands), 1980-1984 and undated (Box W15)
      - Oussedik, Fatima (Algeria), 1982-1983 and undated (Box W15)
      - Papandreou, M. (Greece), 1982-1985 and undated (Box W15)
    - Contributors (Box W16)
      - Park, Sun Chun (South Korea), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W16)
      - Pietila, Hilkka (Finland), 1980-1986 and undated (Box W16)
      - Pineda, Magaly (Spanish speaking Caribbean), 1981-1986 and undated (Box W16)
      - Pintasilgo, Maria de Lourdes (Portugal), 1979-1985 and undated, 2 folders (Box W16)
      - Portugal, Ana Maria (Peru), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W16)
      - Prado, Danda (Brazil), 1979-1985 and undated (Box W16)
      - Quan, Stella (Guatemala), 1982-1984 and undated (Box W16)
      - Rivero, Isel (Cuba), 1980-1981 and undated (Box W16)
    - Contributors (Box W17)
      - Rowley, Maggie and Beatie Hofmeyr (South Africa), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W17)
      - el Saadawi, Nawal (Egypt), 1979-1983 and undated, 2 folders (Box W17)
      - Sanchez, Luz Helena (Colombia), 1981-1983 and undated (Box W17)
      - Savane, Marie A. (Senegal), 1981-1984 and undated (Box W17)
      - Schlaffer, Edit and C. Benard (Austria), 1981-1983 and undated (Box W17)
      - Sebestyen, Amanda (England), 1981-1986 (Box W17)
      - Sumbung, Titi (Indonesia), 1982-1983 and undated (Box W17)
      - Titkow, Anna (Poland), 1981-1983 and undated (Box W17)
      - Vammen, Tinne (Denmark), 1982-1984 and undated (Box W17)
      - Vajrathon, Mallica (Thailand), 1981-1982 and undated (Box W17)
      - Wali, S. (Afganistan), 1981-1984 and undated (Box W17)
    - Contributors (Box W18)
      - Waring, Marilyn and Ngahuia Te Awekotuku (New Zealand), 1981-1984 and undated (Box W18)
      - Yoha Bagbeni Assumani Ussu (Zaire), 1982 and undated (Box W18)
      - Zaccaria, Paola (Italy), 1982-1986 and undated (Box W18)
      - de Zelaya, Merea Lourdes Centeno (Nicaragua), 1981-1985 and undated (Box W18)
    - Reactions, 1984-1985 and undated (Box W18)
    - Press and reviews, 1980s, 2 folders (Box W18)
  - Sisterhood is Powerful Subseries, 1969-2000 and undated
    - Random House correspondence (Production, precis, contract, titles, etc.), 1969-1970 and undated (Box W18)
    - Contributors' correspondence, miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1977 and undated (Box W18)
    - Correspondence re: publicity and promotion, 1969-1970 and undated (Box W18)
    - Foreign rights, 1970-1976 (Box W18)
    - Requests, 1971-1974 and undated, 1 of 3 folders (Box W18)
    - Requests, 1971-1974 and undated, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box W19)
    - General, 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box W19)
    - Contracts and royalty statements, 1973-2000 and undated (Box W19)
    - Inc. Tax, Inc. dissolution, 1971-1976 and undated, 2 folders (Box W19)
    - Lawsuit
      - C. Cisler court action, 1973-1974 and undated (Box W19)
      - Fundraising re: court, 1974-1975 and undated (Box W19)
      - Support re: Cisler case, 1974-1978 and undated (Box W19)
    - Reviews and press, 1970-1972 and undated (Box W19)
    - Report, 1974-1976 and undated (Box W20)
    - 30th anniversary edition, 1999-2000 and undated (Box W20)
  - Poems Subseries, 1946-1999 and undated
    - 1946-1958 and undated:Juvenilia (Box W20)
    - 1950s-1960s: Drafts and variants (Box W20)
    - 1965-1972: Drafts and variants (Box W20)
    - 1977 and undated: Drafts and variants (Box W20)
    - 1980:Drafts (Box W20)
    - 1985 Oct.:"Balefire," "Flying South" (Box W20)
    - 1985 Oct.: "Piecing" (Box W20)
    - 1997:"The Spirit Cellar" (Box W20)
    - 1998 Feb.:"Add-Water Instant Blues" (Box W21)
    - 1998 Summer:"Referred Pain" (Box W21)
    - 1998 Oct.:"Learning Clock Patience" (Box W21)
    - 1998:"Treesitter" (Box W21)
    - 1999 Mar.:"Fair Game," "The Last Time" (Box W21)
    - 1999 May:"Count Down" (Box W21)
    - 1999 Spring:"Invocation" (Box W21)
    - 1999 June:"Samizdat," "Universal Donor" (Box W21)
    - 1999 June/July:"Acrobats and Clowns" (Box W21)
    - 1999 July:"Country Matters," "The Farmer's Wife," "The Butcher's Daughter" (Box W21)
    - 1999 Summer:"Fixed Canon" (Box W21)
    - undated:Drafts, 2 folders (Box W21)
    - undated:Drafts II, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box W21)
    - undated:Drafts II, 3 of folders (Box W22)
    - undated: Monster (Early versions: War Games [I and II], home master, master copy manuscript for printer), 2 folders (Box W22)
    - undated:Unrevised poems in draft for Monster (Box W22)
  - Other Writings by Morgan Subseries, 1940s-2001 and undated, bulk 1970-2001
    - 1940s-1960s:Short stories, 2 folders (Box W22)
    - 1953, 1955:Juvenilia (Box W22)
    - 1961 and undated:Juvenilia [includes Their Own Country] (Box W22)
    - 1963-1964:Reader's reports for Sterling Lord Publishing (Box W22)
    - 1960s: Poems translated from the Vietnamese (Box W22)
    - 1960s-1970s: Sex and Revolution (collaboration of Morgan and Pitchford) (Box W23)
    - 1978 Feb. 28:Vietnamese poems (translation, NYU reading) (Box W23)
    - 1970s:Drafts of articles, 2 folders (Box W23)
    - 1970 and undated: Ms. pieces and memos, 2 folders (Box W23)
    - 1970s:Reactions to Morgan's writings, 2 folders (Box W23)
    - 1970s-1980s and undated:Comments on others (Box W23)
    - 1970s-1980s and undated:Short articles for Ms. (Box W23)
    - 1970s-1980s: Blurbs, comments, and advice on women's books, A-W, 10 folders (Box W24)
    - 1981: Death Benefits Chapbook (Box W24)
    - 1989 and undated:UNDP book on HIV/AIDS (Box W25)
    - 1980s:Short Ms. pieces (Box W25)
    - 1980s:Past World columns (Box W25)
    - 1991:Satire on editorial job (Box W25)
    - 1993-1996 and undated:Overview of U.S. feminism for Reader's Companion to U.S. Women (Box W25)
    - 1999:"Human Here Inside of Me" (Box W25)
    - [19-]:Short articles and correspondence, 2 folders (Box W25)
    - 2000-2001 and undated: Madame Bovary Foreword (Box W25)
    - undated: Their Own Country (Box W25)
    - undated: The Duel (Box W25)
    - undated: The White Haired Witch Draft, 1 of 2 folders (Box W25)
    - undated: The White Haired Witch Draft, 2 of 2 folders (Box W26)
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1964-1970, 1973, 1990s and undated
    - 1964-1970 and undated:Poetry and correspondence for Motive Issue (Box W26)
    - 1973, 1994 and undated:Dissertation and criticism of Morgan (Box W26)
    - 1990s:Wagner, Jane (with comments by Morgan and Tomlin) (Box W26)
  - Grants Subseries, 1970s-1980s
    - 1970s-1980s:Writing grants (Box W26)
    - 1970s-1980s:National Endowment for the Arts (Box W26)
    - 1980s:Guggenheim grant (Box W26)
- Speeches and Interviews Series, 1966-1993 and undated
  Approximately one third of the series consists of drafts of Morgan's speeches; interviews of Morgan by Dorothy Dinnerstein, Chai Lin and Helen Cooper; and material about her joint poetry tour with Kenneth Pitchford. The remaining two thirds of the material is documents related to Morgan's speeches and interviews (chiefly correspondence, schedules, and contracts). All material is in alphabetical order. Several announcements of Morgan's speeches are located in the Oversize Material at the end of the collection.
  - Appearance requests, 1973-1980, 2 folders (Box SP1)
  - Joint poetry tour with Kenneth Pitchford, 1966 (Box SP1)
  - Lectures and readings, 1971-1974, 6 folders (Box SP1)
  - Lectures and readings, 1975-1980, 9 folders (Box SP2)
  - Lectures and readings, 1981, 1987, 2 folders (Box SP3)
  - Meredith lecture, 1992 (Box SP3)
  - Morgan-Chai Lin interview, undated (Box SP3)
  - Morgan-Cooper interview, 1981 (Box SP3)
  - Morgan-Dinnerstein dialogue, 1977-1978 and undated (Box SP3)
  - Philadelphia speech and revolt, 1973 (Box SP3)
  - Speaking engagements and schedule, 1992-1993 (Box SP3)
- Subject Files Series, 1968-2000 and undated
  The Subject Files Series is organized into five subseries. Apart from the International Feminist Activism and Resources Subseries, which is organized by continents, all material within individual subseries is in alphabetical order. Formats include newspaper clippings, ephemeral publications, short articles, and official letters and documents.
  The General Subseries includes documentation about a controversial plagiarism case involving Robin Morgan, as well as material documenting Morgan's service with Hands Across America. The International Feminist Activism and Resources Subseries documents feminist activism all over the world. The most substantial material comes from South Africa and the Middle East, where Morgan spent months in the Palestinian refugee camps. The Ms. Subseries contains minutes and memos from editorial meetings, information about distribution, and some correspondence with readers. A large portion of the subseries comes from the years when Morgan acted as editor-in chief (1989-1993) and re-launched the magazine as an international bimonthly free of advertising. There is also material concerning the 1980 issue of Ms. about Russian women and Soviet feminism. The Sisterhood Is Global Institute Subseries contains some annual reports and other institutional documents. Finally, the U.S. Feminist Activism and Resources Subseries consists of subject files that cover a number of topics, including witchcraft, demonstrations against the Miss America Pageant, women's clinics, and anti-pornography campaigns. There are also several documents about feminist conferences in the United States and some material concerning figures such as Gloria Steinem, Marilyn Waring, and Patricia Hearst. A complete set of issues of Rat magazine was removed from this subseries and is located in the Oversize Materials.
  - General Subseries, 1980s-1996
    - Australian plagiarism controversy, 1995-1996 (Box S1)
    - Hands Across America New York Committee, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S1)
  - International Feminist Activism and Resources Subseries, 1970-1990s and undated
    - Africa
      - General 1989-1993 (Box S1)
      - South Africa
        - Academia, 1990s (Box S1)
        - Cape Town notes, 1990s (Box S1)
        - Clips, 1998 (Box S1)
        - Comparative essays, 1998 and undated, 3 folders (Box S1)
        - Disability, homophobia, women's net, media, 1990s (Box S1)
        - History, 1990s and undated, 2 folders (Box S1)
    - Africa (Box S2)
      - South Africa
        - KwaZulu Natal, 1990s (Box S2)
        - Law/Lobbying, 1997 (Box S2)
        - Local government and GAP, 1990s and undated (Box S2)
        - RSA contacts, 1990s and undated (Box S2)
        - Violence, 1990s, 2 folders (Box S2)
        - Work, farm, SEWU rural, 1990s (Box S2)
    - Asia
      - China, 1995 (Box S2)
      - General, 1990s and undated (Box S2)
      - Philippines, 1990s (Box S2)
    - Europe
      - Bosnia, 1990s, 2 folders (Box S2)
      - France--Issues of Le Torchon Brule, undated (Box S2)
    - Europe (Box S3)
      - General, 1970-1990s and undated (Box S3)
    - General
      - Fundamentalist conference, 1990s (Box S3)
      - Materials about rape, 1973 and undated (Box S3)
    - Middle East
      - Calls and contacts, 1980s and undated (Box S3)
      - Gaza Strip, 1980s (Box S3)
      - General, 1980s, 3 folders (Box S3)
      - General data file, 1980s (Box S3)
      - Israel-US Zionist aggressives, 1984-1986 and undated (Box S3)
      - Jordan, 1985-1986 and undated (Box S3)
      - Lebanon, 1980s (Box S3)
      - Palestine
        - General, 1988 (Box S3)
        - Intifada, 1988 (Box S3)
        - UNDP, 1980s (Box S3)
    - Middle East (Box S4)
      - Palestine
        - UNRWA Data, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S4)
        - Unsorted, 1980s (Box S4)
        - Various articles, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S4)
      - Saudi Arabian women drivers' report, undated (Box S4)
      - Syria, 1980s and undated (Box S4)
      - West Bank, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S4)
    - Pacific
      - General, 1970s-1990s and undated (Box S4)
    - Pacific (Box S5)
      - Marilyn Waring
        - Book accounts, correspondence, critiques, 1985-1987 and undated (Box S5)
        - Correspondence, 1987-1991 and undated (Box S5)
        - Essays book, 1985 (Box S5)
        - Funding, 1985-1986 and undated (Box S5)
        - Lectures, 1982-1986 and undated (Box S5)
        - Speeches, 1992 and undated (Box S5)
      - New Zealand action, 1980s and undated (Box S5)
    - South America
      - Brazil, 1980s-1990s (Box S5)
  - Ms. Subseries, 1970s-1990s and undated
    - Alton Productions, 1992 and undated (Box S5)
    - Ancillary sales, 1990s (Box S5)
    - Board of Scholars, 1990s and undated (Box S5)
    - Book club, 1990s (Box S5)
    - Contributing editor, 1970s, 1 of 2 folders (Box S5)
    - Contributing editor, 1970s, 2 of 2 folders (Box S6)
    - Contributing editors, 1990s (Box S6)
    - Correspondence with Ms. authors, 1970s-1980s (Box S6)
    - Female genital mutilation controversy, 1980s and undated, 2 folders (Box S6)
    - Foreign distribution, 1990s (Box S6)
    - Formats, 1990s (Box S6)
    - General, 1970s-1980s (Box S6)
    - General information, 1990 and undated (Box S6)
    - Interns, 1980s and undated, 2 folders (Box S6)
    - Interns and apprentices, 1980s (Box S6)
    - International Board of Advisors, 1990s (Box S6)
    - International contributing editors' memos, 1990s (Box S6)
    - Inventory Morgan left on leaving Ms., 1993 (Box S6)
    - Issue on Russian women (Box S7)
      - Background and clips, 1980s (Box S7)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box S7)
      - Correspondence with Russian women, 1980s (Box S7)
      - Film project, 1980s (Box S7)
      - Lazarova et al. protests, 1980s (Box S7)
      - Magazine and book rights, 1980 (Box S7)
      - Mammonova US trip, 1980s, 3 folders (Box S7)
      - Ms. copy, 1980 (Box S7)
      - Russian language materials, 1980 and undated (Box S7)
      - Samizdat, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S7)
      - Transcripts, 1980s (Box S7)
    - Lang agreements, 1990s (Box S8)
    - Memos, 1980s (Box S8)
    - Minutes from editorial meetings, 1970s-1980s, 2 folders (Box S8)
    - Morgan memos as editor, 1990s (Box S8)
    - Morgan memos from New Zealand, 1993 (Box S8)
    - O'Shea (dishwashers' strike), 1980s (Box S8)
    - Post Ms. Editorship, 1990s (Box S8)
    - Press coverage, 1990s, 2 folders (Box S8)
    - Press on Ms., 1991 (Box S8)
    - Press on Ms. launch in Australia, 1993 (Box S8)
    - Reactions from staff and readers, and Morgan's correspondence with both, 1990s, 1 of 2 folders (Box S8)
    - Rejections A-F, 1970s-1980s, 3 folders (Box S9)
    - Rejections H-M, 1970s-1980s, 2 folders (Box S9)
    - Rejections N-R, 1970s-1980s, 2 folders (Box S9)
    - Rejections S-Z, 1970s-1980s, 1 of 2 folders (Box S9)
    - Rejections S-Z, 1970s-1980s, 2 of 2 folders (Box S10)
    - Responses to re-launched Ms. with Morgan as editor, 1990s (Box S10)
    - Ruth Bower meetings, 1990s (Box S10)
    - Ruth Bower memos, 1990s, 2 folders (Box S10)
    - Steinem Book complaints, 1992-1993 (Box S10)
    - Television project, 1992 (Box S10)
    - Unsorted materials, 1990-1994, 3 folders (Box S10)
  - Sisterhood is Global Institute Subseries, 1980s-1999 and undated
    - Annual Report, 1999 (Box S11)
    - Church Women United Foundation, 1982 (Box S11)
    - Conference, 1984, 3 folders (Box S11)
    - Conference, 1984-1985, 4 folders (Box S11)
    - Conference confirmation cables, undated (Box S11)
    - Conference materials, 1984 (Box S11)
    - Conference responses, 1984 and undated (Box S11)
    - Drafts, participants, 1984 and undated (Box S11)
    - Financial information, 1999 (Box S11)
    - Ford Foundation, 1981-1987 and undated, 1 of 2 folders (Box S11)
    - Ford Foundation, 1981-1987 and undated, 2 of 2 folders (Box S12)
    - Foundation rejections, 1981-1984 and undated, 2 folders (Box S12)
    - Funding
      - Alida Brill, 1981-1984 and undated (Box S12)
      - Carnegie, 1981-1982 and undated (Box S12)
      - Methodists, 1982-1983 and undated (Box S12)
    - Funding rejections for SIGI meeting, 1984 and undated, 2 folders (Box S12)
    - Grants pending, 1983 and undated (Box S12)
    - Grants received, 1982-1989 and undated (Box S12)
    - Grant rejections, 1981-1988 and undated, 2 folders (Box S12)
    - Institutional Documents (vol. 1), 1999, 3 folders (Box S13)
    - Institutional Documents (vol. 2), 1999, 3 folders (Box S13)
    - Invitations: Press conference, 1984 (Box S13)
    - Invitations to strategy meeting, 1984 and undated (Box S13)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1980s-1990s (Box S13)
    - Members A-Z, 1980s-1990s and undated, 1-2 of 7 folders (Box S13)
    - Members A-Z, 1980s-1990s and undated, 3-7 of 7 folders (Box S14)
    - Panels, 1984 and undated (Box S14)
    - Participation letter and packet, 1985 and undated (Box S14)
    - Party invitations and list, undated (Box S14)
    - Press conference, 1984 (Box S14)
    - Press follow-up, 1984 and undated (Box S14)
    - Press mailing lists undated (Box S14)
    - Shalala Party, 1985 and undated (Box S14)
    - Skaggs Foundation, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S14)
    - Statement and draft, undated (Box S15)
    - Steering Committee meeting, 1999 (Box S15)
    - Strategy meeting, 1984 Nov. 11-16, 6 folders (Box S15)
    - Transition binder, 1999 (Box S15)
  - U.S. Feminist Activism and Resources Subseries, 1968-2000 and undated
    - Conferences
      - de Beauvoir conference, 1979 (Box S15)
      - Canadian conference, 1983 (Box S15)
      - Lesbian conference in Los Angeles, 1972-1973, 5 folders (Box S15)
    - Conferences (Box S16)
      - Wise Women's conference, 1985 (Box S16)
    - Controversies
      - Chesler, Phyllis, 1980s (Box S16)
      - Hearst, Patricia, 1980s, 2 folders (Box S16)
      - Steinem, Gloria
        - 1979 (Box S16)
        - 1970s, 2 folders (Box S16)
        - New Zealand trip controversy, 1977 (Box S16)
    - Controversies (Box S17)
      - Swinton Trial (Saxe), 1975-1976 and undated, 2 folders (Box S17)
    - Demonstrations
      - Miss America, 1968-1969, 3 folders (Box S17)
    - General
      - Anti-porn, 1970s-1980s, 4 folders (Box S17)
      - Bella Abzug
        - 1977-1979, undated (Box S17)
    - General (Box S18)
      - Bella Abzug
        - Congressional campaign
          - 1986, undated (Box S18)
          - 1992, undated (Box S18)
      - Feminist organizing papers, 1980s-1990s and undated (Box S18)
      - Grove Press action, 1970, 2 folders (Box S18)
      - Guerrilla Girls, undated (Box S18)
      - Lesbian theory and activism, 1980s (Box S18)
      - Medical self-Help clinics, 1970s (Box S18)
      - NY Women's Rights Center, 1970s and undated (Box S18)
      - Up From Under, 1970-1973, 3 folders (Box S18)
    - General (Box S19)
      - Web magazine project, 2000 (Box S19)
      - Wicca, 1970s and undated, 3 folders (Box S19)
      - Witch materials, 1968-1972 and undated (Box S19)
      - Women's Studies stuff, 1970s (Box S19)
- Personal Files Series, 1950s-1989 and undated
  Consists primarily of papers related to Robin Morgan's formal education at Columbia University. Formats include class notes, essays, and rather brief notebooks from her trips to the Middle East, Austria and Egypt, further documented in the Photographic and Visual Materials Series and Subject Files Series. Other material includes FBI and CIA files, which Morgan requested through the Freedom of Information Act in the 1970s. Each of the three categories (Education at Columbia University, Trips, and Other Personal) is arranged in chronological order.
  - Education at Columbia University (Box PER1)
    - 1957:Psychology, 2 folders (Box PER1)
    - 1958:Anthropology, 2 folders (Box PER1)
    - 1958:German (Box PER1)
    - 1958:Victorian Literature (Box PER1)
    - 1958-1959:Renaissance Literature (Box PER1)
    - 1959:Art of Poetry (Box PER1)
    - 1959:Civilization and Culture (Box PER1)
    - 1950s-1960s:Essays and school papers, 2 folders (Box PER1)
  - Education at Columbia University (Box PER2)
    - 1960:English (Box PER2)
    - 1960:Exam (Box PER2)
  - Trips
    - 1978-1979:Aborted Iran trip (Box PER2)
    - 1985-1986 and undated:Mid-East trip maps and itineraries (Box PER2)
    - 1989:Palestine/Israel notebook (Box PER2)
    - undated:Jerusalem notebook (Box PER2)
    - undated:Jordan notebook (Box PER2)
    - undated:Vienna and Cairo notebook (Box PER2)
  - Other Personal
    - 1962:Apartment lease (Box PER2)
    - 1976-1978:FBI and CIA files, 2 folders (Box PER2)
- Teaching Materials Series, 1971-1998 and undated, bulk 1995-1997
  Includes material related to Robin Morgan's position as an adjunct professor at the Union Graduate School; as a visiting chair and guest professor of Women's Studies at New College (Sarasota, Fla.); and as a visiting professor at the University of Denver Graduate School of International Affairs. The bulk comes from the Denver position and includes contracts; course material related both to the courses that Morgan attended and to the courses she taught on feminism; student papers; and teaching-related correspondence. The material is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - New College, Fla. 1971-1972, 4 folders (Box T1)
  - Union Graduate School, 1974 (Box T1)
  - University of Denver
    - Books and references, 1996-1997 and undated, 4 folders (Box T1)
    - Contacts, 1996-1997 and undated (Box T1)
    - Contracts and original correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box T1)
    - Extra curriculum appears, 1997 and undated (Box T1)
    - General, 1996-1998, 1 of 3 folders (Box T1)
  - University of Denver (Box T2)
    - General, 1996-1998, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box T2)
    - Graduate course in communications (correspondence), 1996-1997 (Box T2)
    - Graduate School International Studies, 1996-1997 and undated (Box T2)
    - Provost lecture, 1997 (Box T2)